Folder inventory to the Marcus Raskin papers, 1952-2013 MS2297
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Marcus Raskin papers
1949-2013
1959-1963
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Raskin, Marcus G.
MS2297
20 Linear Feet 19 record center boxes, 2 document boxes
This collection contains correspondence, articles, lecture notes, essays, biographical data, and subject and research files. These materials represent the personal papers of Marcus Raskin, the materials he created and collected with the Institute for Policy Studies and as a professor at The George Washington University. The materials date from 1949-2013.
Arrangement
Organized into 9 series: Biographical data; Writings (by Marcus Raskin and collected by him); Lectures, conferences, and seminars; Institute for Policy Studies; PATHS; Correspondence; People; Subject and research files, and The Liberal Project.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Marcus and Lynn Raskin, 2011 September 26 (2011.064)
Biographical note
Marcus Raskin (b. 1934-2017 ) is the co-founder of the progressive think tank, the Institute for Policy Studies, located in Washington, DC and an author of numerous books and articles. In 1961 Harvard sociologist David Riesman recommended Raskin, a recent graduate of the University of Chicago Law School, to McGeorge Bundy, the National Security Advisor to the newly elected president, John F. Kennedy. Raskin served as Bundy's assistant on national security affairs and disarmament as a member of the Special Staff of the National Security Council. In 1963, Raskin left government service and founded, with fellow government worker Richard Barnet, the Institute for Policy Studies (IPS). Much of Raskin's initial work with IPS focused on opposing the Vietnam War. He co-authored The Viet-nam Reader with Bernard Fall in 1965, which was used in dozens of teach-ins across the country.
Marcus Raskin is the author and co-author of more than twenty books and countless articles related to the progressive movement including topics such as as anti-war, liberalism, anti-nuclear movement, and pro-environment.
He is also a professor of public policy at The George Washington University's School of Public Policy and Public Administration.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, articles, lecture notes, essays, biographical data, and subject and research files. These materials represent the personal papers of Marcus Raskin, the materials he created and collected with the Institute for Policy Studies and as a professor at The George Washington University. The materials date from 1949-2013.
Other Finding Aid
http://library.gwu.edu/ead/ms2349.xml Institute for Policy Studies Marcus Raskin files
Liberalism; Institute for Policy Studies
- Biographical data, 1961-2005; Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains folders with biographical information for Marcus Raskin. These files are dated 1961-2005.
  - Kennedy Bird, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Who's Who, 2005; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Composer Comments, September 6, 2003; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Raskin Biography, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Piano Composition- American Requiem, 1999-2000; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Raskin family tree, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The "Dictionary", October 1988; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Security Council: Personal History Statement, 1961; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Seymour Melman Memorial at Columbia, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Writings (by Marcus Raskin and collected by him), 1949-2011; Series 2
  This series contains articles and essays written by Marcus Raskin. It also contains articles and essays written by other authors that Marcus Raskin collected possibly for research. The folders are mostly undated. The folders with dates range from 1949-2011.
  - Democracy versus The National Security State, 1978; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Raskin Essays, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Left Project Essay V+R, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Let's Terminate the CIA, June 8, 1992; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mediation on Anti-Semitism, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Memoirs (fictitious), undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Metamorphosis, 1994; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Op-Ed Proposal, April 25, 1995; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - National Security and Domestic Reconstruction (Draft), undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Notes on Evil and Nuremberg, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nuclear Weapons, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - President Clinton's Small Change (Original), undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Racial Justice and Affirmative Action, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Richard Falk: Regionalism and World Order After the Cold War, August 23-24, 1994; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Reinventing the Left, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Republic or Democracy- New York Times, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Revisiting the National Security Act, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Secrecy, February 26, 1995; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Arthur Mitzman: Thoughts on the Second Millenium, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bill Cannon's Toward a New Economics, September 9, 1993; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - When Does A War End?, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 2 Papers, 1992; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Citicorp Additions, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Authur S. Link's Woodrow Wilson, 1979; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Statement on Amendment Process for the District Elements of Comprehensive Plan, 1996; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Essay on Iran Contra, undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Twentieth Century Journey, 1989; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - This is my Century, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Twentieth Century Journey, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 20th Century Book, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Abortion, 1986; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Rosenstein Squatting, November 7, 1993; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Build the American Home: Housing and Social Reconstruction, 1993; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Dick Sclove: Technology and Freedom, 1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Accountability: Essay with Anabel, 1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - American Historical Review: Responses to JFK, October 1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Op-Ed Balancing the Budget, 1996; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    General
    This folder contains topics in policy research.
  - Call to the Left (for the Nation), 1995; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - CIA Article, 1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Op-Ed Laby, McNamara, and Vietnam, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Op-Ed Death Penalty, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Essay on Disarmament, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - V+R Building the American Home, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - The Common Good, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - National Security: Its Emergence as an Instrument of State Policy, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Research and Action Program for Democratic Social Reconstruction, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Secrecy- by Stanley Goldberg, April 1994; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lippmann and Bundy on The Good Society, June 6, 1949; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Democracy, Law, and the State, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Puddy's Memoir- Draft 2, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Liberalism Book, 1999; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - First Principles: Draft, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Booknotes for First Principles, September 1995; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Raskin- Landau Film Script, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Film, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Multicultural Democracy, Family, and Community without Sentimentality, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Preface to Subversive Liberalism, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Notebooks, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Liberalism and Post Democracy, January 1997; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Is there a Liberal Answer?, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Liberalism Part 1, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Libreralism Part 2, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Finding Paths Through the Concrete: Changing Social Character, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Draft of Liberalism, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Footnotes and Research, 1998; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Beyond Brenton Woods, 1994; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Calling the Shots: How Washington Dominates Today's U.N., undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Raskin Drafts, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Opportunist (Part 1), 1992; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Opportunist (Part 2), 1992; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Opportunist (Part 3), 1992; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Untitled Manuscript, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Visions and Revisions, 1995; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - John Dewey and Reconstruction, April 12, 1991; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Essays Vol. 2, 1974; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Essays Vol. 3, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Raskin Writings, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - The Vision Thing, 1995; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Race, 1995; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Reconstructive Knowledge, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Reconstructive Knowledge Book Ideas, 1995; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Reconstruction Articles from Inquiry Group, April 27/28, 1994; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Social Reconstruction, 1983; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Nuclear Test Ban Paper, 1961; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy and Public Policy Quarterly, 2005; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Discussion Draft, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Baumbach- Adventures of Josh and Juniata, 2004-2005; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Raskin Memories and Events, March 19, 2006; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Raskin Writings, 2005; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - In Democracy's Shadow #1, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - In Democracy's Shadow #2, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Insider/Outsider, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Iraq Support and Dissent, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Articles, 2005; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Interesting Papers, 2006; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Reconstructive Knowledge, 1991; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Raskin and Levan Introduction, 2001- 2002; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Raskin and Levan Introduction, January 28, 2002; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - It's Your Freedom- If You Can Keep It, 1941- 2002; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Issues and Questions- Democracy, Law, and the State, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - John Dewey and Recontruction, April 12, 1991; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - War Systems: Conditions of Decency, 2007; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Insider Outsider: Memoir, August 2007; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - In Democracy's Shadow, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Four Freedoms, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Various Writings, 2001; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Chomsky the Wise: Raskin, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Chomsky the Wise Additions, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Seymour Melman: What a Man is For, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Raskin, Patrick, Chomsky, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Various Writings, 1994-2011; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - From Private to State Capitalism: Seymour Melman, January 4, 1997; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Lib-book 72-98, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Untitled- Raskin Writings, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Raskin Writings- Unpublished, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Preface Y and Z, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Various Writings, 1975-2009; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Path for Reconstruction, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Metaphorical Glass- Raskin and Spero, 2008; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Reconstructive Inquiry- Raskin and Frens-String, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Various Articles, 2002-2007; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Various Papers, 1995-2008; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Various Papers- General Grant D.C., 1998-2000; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Draft- Liberal Papers, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Journal of Marketing, 1983; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Reconstructive Knowledge, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Liberalism Draft Part 3, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Cyber War is Coming!, 1993; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Peace Movement Vietnam War, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - The Practice of Hope, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - When Computers Were Human, 2002; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Italian Newspaper Interview, 2007; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Raskin Autobiography, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Interesting Readings, 2001-2002; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Community Section for Liberalism, 1993-1995; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Science and National Security, 1950-2007; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Globalization, 1999; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Raskin Reviews, 1987-1993; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Unprocessed Materials, undated; Series 2 (Box 19)
- Lectures, conferences, and seminars, 1989-2009; Series 3
  This series contains information about lectures, conferences and seminars. These are primarily events in which Marcus Raskin was a participant. These folders date from 1989-2009.
  - Session II: "Importance of Capital Formation to Urban Growth", December 1995; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - International Conference on the Horn of Africa, 1989; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Affirmative Action Conference and National Crime Symposium, 1989-1992; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Speech: The Twenty First Century University in American Democracy, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Conference of Reconstructive Public, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Reconstruction: A Program, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - D.C. Group, 1995-1996; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - D.C. Seminar- GW, 1996; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Conference on Reconstructive Policy Analysis, 1999-2000; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - National Security Book and Seminar, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - GW National Security State Seminar, 1995-1996; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - GW Seminar on Knowledge, 1996; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - GW National Security State Seminar, 1994-1995; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - GW Class on National Security State, 1994; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Left Project Ideas for Seminar, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lecture Series on Visions and Revisions, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - GW Paths 1st Principle Seminar, 1993-1995; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Reconstruction: Lecture at Amherst College, 1991; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Rothko Chapel Lecture- War on Terror and Torture, 2004; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - United Nations/ GW Speaker, January 22, 2002; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Lecture on Democracy, April 2, 2009; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Lecture and Conversations with Marcus Raskin- Chapel Talk, 2003-2005; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Speech at George Mason University, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Remarks at Cliburn competition, 1999 June 11; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 14.5)
  - Speech at Rothco Chapel, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Judgement and Public Policy Course, 2007; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Public Policy 285, 2004; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Public Policy 285, 2008; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Public Policy 285, 2007; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - GW Course with Squires, 2007; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Various Seminars, 1995-1997; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Judgement, 2008; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - National Defense University: Rethinking and Resourcing the "Long War", 1995-2007; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Social Collapse- Italian Lecture, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Stoker Conference, 1999; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Seminar Notes, 1999; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - District of Columbia, May 15-17, 1998; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - National Security and Democracy, November 26, 1990; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Speech Notes for the State University of New York at Albany, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Gandhi/Contextualizing, 2000-2001; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Lecture at the University of Massachusetts on National Security State and Post Modern Cold War Situation, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Democracy Conference (Transcript)- Part 1, November 1990; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Democracy Conference (Transcript)- Part 2, November 1990; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Democracy Conference (Transcript)- Part 3, November 1990; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Freedom of Speech: Other Topics for Conversation, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Forum Discussion, 2006; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Public Policy 285, 2005; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Seminar of Making Public Policies, 2004; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Rothko Talk/Lecture, undated; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Institute for Policy Studies, 1963-2012; Series 4
  Historical note
  The Institute for Policy Studies, a left-leaning think tank, was founded in 1963 by Marcus Raskin and Richard Barnet. The two were Kennedy administration staff members who formed the IPS in an attempt to persaude government policy-makers to embrace progressive ideas. By 1965, IPS, was fully involved in the anti-Vietnam War movement. Raskin and Bernard Fall, an IPS fellow, edited The Viet-Nam Reader which became an essential text for the teach-in movement that was sweeping across college campuses.Over the years, the IPS has become a place to generate and test progressive ideas. Some ideas such as the Model Cities program and Teachers Corps became policy. Throughout its life-time, IPS scholars have written books, produced films, and lead social movements all with the goal of educating and influencing key policymakers and the general public. Areas of focus have been peace, justice, and the environment. The principles articulated by Raskin and Barnet for IPS included: not taking government funding to ensure impartiality, public scholarship, building alternatives, and social inventions.
  This series contains information about the Institute for Policy Studies between 1963-2012.
  - Raskin/ IPS Mementos, 1988; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - IPS, 1996; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Foreign Policy, 1963; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - IPS Superfund, August 28, 1995; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - IPS Memos, 1990-1995; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - IPS Raskin Memos, 1995; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - IPS Projects, 1977-1997; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Green Papers, August 1975; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Dinner and Jokes with Marcus Raskin by IPS, February 9, 2012; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - IPS, 1967-1995; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - IPS Development Strategy, May 26, 1999; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Clippings- Marc IPS, 1991-1993; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - IPS: Democrats and IPS Positions, undated; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - IPS, 2006-2007; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - A Foreign Policy Primer (IPS), undated; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Paths, 1975-2004; Series 5
  Marcus Raskin serves as the director of the Institute for Policy Studies' Paths for the 21st Century Project. The Paths for Reconstruction in the 21st Century project links knowledge to the betterment of the human condition through thinking and practical action. The project is based on the assumption that a renaissance of moral action and thought is on the immediate horizon. The PATHS project has produced a multi-volume book that explores international organizations and politics in order to create new models for fostering equality and alternatives for the 21st century on questions of peace, economic and social justice, cultural rights, democratic reconstruction, and racial and gender equality.
  http://www.ips-dc.org/paths
  This series contains folders with information about PATHS. The material dates from 1975-2004.
  - PATHS Proposal, 1995; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - PATHS Budget Drafts, 1994-2001; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - PATHS Participants Lista, December 1994; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - PATHS List of Invitees, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - PATHS Correspondence, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - PATHS Calendars, 1994; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Puzzles and PATHS Proposal (1st Principles), undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Raskin's Notes to Himself on PATHS, October 14, 1994; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - 1st Principles: Introduction, February 12, 1994; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - 1st Principles/ War, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - PATHS: Family- 1st Principles, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Comments 1st Principles, 1995; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - The Free Press (PATHS), 1995; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - PATHS Book Proposal: Economic Justice- Albert and Hahnel, August 3, 1995; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - PATHS Bibliographies: Sources, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - PATHS Study Circles Resource Center, 1996; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - PATHS Study Materials, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - PATHS: Film and Video, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - PATHS Video: Violence in the Post Office, October 14, 1993; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - PATHS: Elegy to the Cold War Tape- A Comment, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Liberalism- PATHS Lecture, 1997; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - PATHS Proposals, 1992-1993; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - PATHS Proposals, 1994; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - PATHS Conference: White Oak, March 1995; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Origina PATHS Letter of Invitation, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - 1st PATHS Letter and Correspondence, 1993; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - PATHS Proposal Draft, 1993; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - PATHS, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - PATHS, 1975; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - PATHS Book List, 1993; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - PATHS Responses to Invitations, 1993; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - PATHS, 1992; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Notes on Encyclopedia- SAW, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Health (PATHS, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - PATHS Proposal- Short, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - PATHS Questions, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Reconstruction/ PATHS, 1977-2001; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Encyclopedia- PATHS (Part 1 of 2), 1989; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Encyclopedia- PATHS (Part 2 of 2), 1989; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Essays, undated; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - PATHS and Puzzles, 1994; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - PATHS, undated; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - PATHS Book Proposal on Economic Justice- Albert and Hahnel, undated; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - PATHS Projects (1 of 3), undated; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - PATHS Projects (2 of 3), undated; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - PATHS Projects (3 of 3), 2005-2006; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - PATHS Inquiry Group Meetings, 1996-2001; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - PATHS Labor and Study Groups, 1995; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 9)